<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diagoge</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://mo-tom.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 13:44:35 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 13:44:35 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Letter to Mr. Zuckerberg</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr. Zuckerberg,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my home country Austria we live in strange times. In recent years in politics, a lot of hate is building up against refugees, and foreign residents. One of the main drivers of this trend is the far-right party FPÖ (Austrian Freedom Party).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Facebook comes in the equation. Besides a lot of nationalist-chauvinist, anti-islam hate-speech-pages being around on Facebook, there is one particular worrying one: The page one of the head of the FPÖ, Mr. HC Strache (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/HCStrache&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/HCStrache&lt;/a&gt;). What is especially disturbing are not his postings – he knows how to disguise hate-speech, after all he’s a politician – but the comments by the followers/visitors of his page. The amount of savagery in the slurs of many of these people is unbearable for every citizen who believes in the dignity and rights of humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would a person utter these statements in public, lets say TV, newspaper or radio, some of them would even be worthy of criminal prosecution under Austrian criminal law. But not so on the internet, because of the sheer number of comments, and the too large effort that would have to be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now many people I know or heard of, including myself, tried to flag these comments on basis of Facebook’s community standards regarding hate-speech. But success has so far been minimal. Often the response we get is simply that reviewers did not find the standards to be applicable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to see for yourself you can visit the website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eaudestrache.at/&quot;&gt;http://www.eaudestrache.at/&lt;/a&gt; where activits highlight the madness, frustration and abomination against human rights and civil standards speaking from these comments by simply aggregating them and putting them on display in large bold fonts. (As most of them are not only written in German but in a bad style and/or hard to decode dialectal form I’m more than willing to assist in translating them for you.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The famous philosopher and novelist Umberto Eco lately lamented in a public lecture that he fears that the internet is more and more becoming a platform for “legions of idiots who formerly only chatted in bars after a glas of wine without hurting the body politic.” Although I consider it a privilege to live in a world where so much information is available on my fingertips and I can connect with virtually anyone on the planet, when I look at the hate on the pages mentioned above that is self-referentially growing and becoming worse I fear that he’s got a case in point there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you or someone of your company can have a look at this and it will be taken as seriously as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you. Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Moser&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. I will put this letter on my personal webpage &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diagoge.com&quot;&gt;http://www.diagoge.com&lt;/a&gt; for the public to read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//letters/A-Letter-to-Mr.-Zuckerberg.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mo-tom.github.io//letters/A-Letter-to-Mr.-Zuckerberg.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>letters</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is war on the way out?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Is war on the way out? Intuition tells us, no way, just watch the news and you’ll hear about all kinds of horrific conflicts. But Joshua Goldstein and Steven Pinker say they looked at the numbers and found evidence that actually, globally there’s a declining trend in violence and wars. What are their arguments, and do they make sense? A distinguished Harvard university panel comprising the authors, the international relations scholars Monica Toft and Stephen Walt, and hosted by Joseph Nye is discussing the inclination of human nature towards violence and the past, present, and possible future of organized armed conflict. Well worth watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KZWvyBuvKX0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/is-war-on-the-way-out%3F.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/is-war-on-the-way-out%3F.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two cent review of Piketty&#39;s &#39;Capital in the Twenty-First Century&#39;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A spectre is haunting the review pages – the spectre of &lt;em&gt;Capital in the Twenty-First Century&lt;/em&gt;. This is the title of a book by the French economist Thomas Piketty. About two months after its release, it’s already an all time bestseller for Harvard University Press (Belknap) who sold 41,000 copies and counting – which is quite remarkable for an +600 pages academic publication (albeit intended for a wider circle of ‘interested’ individuals). This fact alone shows how timely this publication is for the debates about capitalism’s ‘new normal’ and its future after the Great Financial Crisis which unearthed and in many cases accelerated the economic disruptions that mounted at least since the mid 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, it challenges the mainstream view that capitalism is creating prosperity not only for a few on the top but for a broad middle class. This view is connected to the work of Simon Smith Kuznets who argued that even though inequality will rise when a country’s economy is ‘taking off’ it will come down after some time. This theory can be visualized as the so-called Kuznets-Curve (below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/kuznets-curve.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kuznets curve&quot; class=&quot;pimg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This essentially putt an end (at least in mainstream economic theory) to the discussion stemming from Marx whether at the core of capitalism lies an inherent contradiction which will eventually bring about its own demise. Namely that the logic of competition within the accumulative process of capital formation forces down wages what leads to an ever-increasing class division between the bourgeoisie (few) and the proletariat (many)—until the latter will revolt and overcome the whole capitalist system of production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Kuznets the Marxist ‘immiseration thesis’ was replaced by the brighter prospect of (Fordist) capitalism producing a ‘&lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;leveled middle class society’ (Helmut Schelsky). At the time, this not only was an appealing theory for entrepreneurs but also for western politicians as a ‘marketing device’ during the Cold War’s ‘East-West competition’.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Piketty thinks the methodological approach employed by Kuznets was and is sound but there were shortcomings in regard to the dataset used. Kuznets only dealt with one country, the United States, and just for a brief period of 35 years from 1913 to 1948. Piketty says in retrospect this was misleading because the fall in inequality after the Second World War observed by Kuznets corresponds to what in France is called the ‘trente glorieuses’ (aka ‘the golden age of capitalism’ or (German) ‘Wirtschaftswunder’; i.e. the glorious period between 1945 and 1975).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where we arrive at the common consensus about Piketty’s unquestionable achievement. He and some colleagues invested much time in reconstructing the income distribution for a much larger time frame. This opens up a space for analysis that was never available before because there simply wasn’t any such comprehensive (in terms of time and number of countries) dataset available. This broader view shows that Kuznets argument loses its persuasiveness because we see a return of inequality since at least the 1980s on a scale not seen since the 1920s. The graph below shows the amount of inequality measured as the share of national income of the top 10% with the (short-term) inverted U-shape observed by Kuznets (in red) and the (long-term) U-shape revealed by Piketty (in blue).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/us-inequality.png&quot; alt=&quot;US inequality&quot; class=&quot;pimg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contemplating on the historical record Picketty then arrives at a very simple–but by its implications highly provocative–formula: &lt;em&gt;r&amp;gt;g&lt;/em&gt;. What this means is that the rate of return (&lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt;) on capital is greater than the rate of economic growth (&lt;em&gt;g&lt;/em&gt;). So even though we witness reduced rates growth since the 1970s (main factors are declining population growth and slower technological change) the rate of return of capital is not falling in lockstep but at a slower pace which in turn widens the equality gap. But in contrast to Marx who thought in terms of inescapable contradictions of the capitalist mode of production as such Piketty places emphasis on the role of politics in the equation. In other words we can choose which future path our societies, either towards a new ‘patrimonial’ capitalism with levels of inequality never seen before or a comeback of more egalitarian policies that bring inequality down to an eligible level. Along this line the main policy prescription Piketty suggests is a global wealth tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Piketty’s analysis spearheads the critique of neoliberal advocacy of ‘trickle down’ economics, i.e. the belief that reduced taxes on wealth, inheritance, and top incomes would boost investment and consumption and thus create new businesses and jobs and by this means a thriving middle class. He shows that this is simply false; or as I would prefer to call it: ideology. There have been many critics of neoliberalism since the 1970s but until now none has been able to do it with such empirical rigor. I doubt that this will save Piketty from a right-wing ‘shitstorm’–for lack of a better word–but for many it will relieve the critique of the overall economic policy during the past 30 years from the accusation of being a fringe leftist fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets hope Piketty’s book gives a reality check to those who believed that distribution doesn’t matter because the (neoclassical) theory says everyone’s income corresponds to their marginal product.  An alternative title for Piketty’s book could thus have been: &lt;em&gt;Putting Distribution back into Economics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-notable-reviews&quot;&gt;Some notable reviews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pro&quot;&gt;Pro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mpra.ub.uni-muenchen.de/52384/1/MPRA_paper_52384.pdf&quot;&gt;Branko Milanovic: “The return of ‘patrimonial capitalism’. Review of Thomas Piketty’s Capital in the 21st century.” &lt;em&gt;MPRA&lt;/em&gt; Paper No. 52384.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nybooks.com/articles/archives/2014/may/08/thomas-piketty-new-gilded-age/?insrc=hpma&quot;&gt;Paul Krugman: “Why We’re in a New Gilded Age.” &lt;em&gt;NYRB&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dissentmagazine.org/article/kapital-for-the-twenty-first-century&quot;&gt;James K. Galbraith: “&lt;em&gt;Kapital&lt;/em&gt; for the Twenty-First Century?” &lt;em&gt;Dissent&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newrepublic.com/article/117429/capital-twenty-first-century-thomas-piketty-reviewed&quot;&gt;Robert M. Solow: “Thomas Piketty Is Right. Everything you need to know about ‘Capital in the Twenty-First Century’.” &lt;em&gt;New Republic&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ft.com/intl/cms/s/2/875155ce-8f25-11e3-be85-00144feab7de.html#axzz2tWpMyiwH&quot;&gt;Lawrence Summers: “America risks becoming a Downton Abbey economy.” &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/0c6e9302-c3e2-11e3-a8e0-00144feabdc0.html#axzz2zc8Nx0gY&quot;&gt;Martin Wolf: “‘Capital in the Twenty-First Century’, by Thomas Piketty.” &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/arts/critics/books/2014/03/31/140331crbo_books_cassidy?currentPage=all&quot;&gt;John Cassidy: “Forces of Divergence. Is surging inequality endemic to capitalism?” &lt;em&gt;New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;contra&quot;&gt;Contra&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hoover.org/publications/defining-ideas/article/176016&quot;&gt;Allan H. Meltzer: “The United States of Envy.” &lt;em&gt;Defining Ideas&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/joshuarhendrickson/research/PikettyReview.pdf?attredirects=0&quot;&gt;Joshua R. Hendrickson: “Review of Piketty’s Capital in the 21st Century.” &lt;em&gt;National Review&lt;/em&gt; (forthcoming).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/scottwinship/2014/04/17/whither-the-bottom-90-percent-thomas-piketty/&quot;&gt;Scott Winship: “Whither The Bottom 90 Percent, Thomas Piketty?” &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674430006&quot;&gt;Harvard University Press’s website&lt;/a&gt; for more links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;piketty-stiglitz-krugman-discussing-capital-in-the-twenty-first-century-at-cuny&quot;&gt;Piketty, Stiglitz, Krugman discussing  ‘Capital in the Twenty-First Century’ at CUNY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/heOVJM2JZxI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/two-cent-review-of-pikettys-capital-in-the-twenty-first-century.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/two-cent-review-of-pikettys-capital-in-the-twenty-first-century.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NSA PRISM scandal—a primer</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;articles-that-broke-the-story&quot;&gt;Articles that broke the story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/jun/06/us-tech-giants-nsa-data&quot;&gt;NSA Prism program taps in to user data of Apple, Google and others (&lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/us-intelligence-mining-data-from-nine-us-internet-companies-in-broad-secret-program/2013/06/06/3a0c0da8-cebf-11e2-8845-d970ccb04497_story.html?hpid=z1&quot;&gt;U.S., British intelligence mining data from nine U.S. Internet companies in broad secret program (&lt;em&gt;WaPo&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whos-edward-snowden-and-how-did-the-story-evolve&quot;&gt;Who’s Edward Snowden and how did the story evolve?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/jun/09/edward-snowden-nsa-whistleblower-surveillance&quot;&gt;Edward Snowden: the whistleblower behind the NSA surveillance revelations (&lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2013/06/11/us/how-edward-j-snowden-orchestrated-a-blockbuster-story.html?partner=rss&amp;amp;emc=rss&amp;amp;_r=0&amp;amp;pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;Cryptic Overtures and a Clandestine Meeting Gave Birth to a Blockbuster Story (&lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/2013/06/10/qa_with_laura_poitras_the_woman_behind_the_nsa_scoops/&quot;&gt;How we broke the NSA story (&lt;em&gt;Salon&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments-pro-and-contra&quot;&gt;Comments, pro and contra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2013/jun/10/edward-snowden-united-stasi-america&quot;&gt;Daniel Ellsberg: Edward Snowden: saving us from the United Stasi of America (&lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/comment/2013/06/edward-snowden-nsa-leaker-is-no-hero.html&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Toobin: Edward Snowden is no Hero (&lt;em&gt;New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-broader-context-and-historical-background&quot;&gt;The broader context and historical background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://projects.propublica.org/graphics/surveillance-timeline&quot;&gt;Mass Surveillance in America: A Timeline of Loosening Laws and Practices (&lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/the-best-stories-on-the-governments-growing-surveillance&quot;&gt;The Best Stories on the Government’s Growing Surveillance (&lt;em&gt;ProPublica&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2012/08/23/opinion/the-national-security-agencys-domestic-spying-program.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;The Program (&lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/threatlevel/2012/03/ff_nsadatacenter/all/1&quot;&gt;The NSA Is Building the Country’s Biggest Spy Center (Watch What You Say) (&lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.washingtonpost.com/top-secret-america/&quot;&gt;Top Secret America - A Washington Post Investigation (&lt;em&gt;WaPo&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/nsa-prism-a-primer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/nsa-prism-a-primer.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>For they do not know what they are doing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two charts show what kind of &lt;strong&gt;naive optimism&lt;/strong&gt; that dominates the institutional brains of policy apparatuses like IMF, EC etc.
First the downward revisions of IMF’s forecasts about the GDP of selected euro zone countries:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/imf-forecast.png&quot; alt=&quot;IMF forecast&quot; class=&quot;pimg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And another of those charts that make you palm-slap your forehead. The Troika’s forecasts about development in Greece:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/troika-forecast.png&quot; alt=&quot;Troika Forecast for Greece&quot; class=&quot;pimg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time there’s this ‘the emperor’s new clothes’-moment when some official at a press-conference is trying to calm everybody with some voodoo-like forecast-optimism remember this passage from Orwell’s novel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Party said that Oceania had never been in alliance with Eurasia. He, Winston Smith, knew that Oceania had been in alliance with Eurasia as short as four years ago. But where did that knowledge exist? Only in his own consciousness, which in any case must soon be annihilated. And if all others accepted the lie which the Party imposed–if all records told the same tale–then the lie passed into history became the truth. ‘Who controls the past,’ ran the Party slogan, ‘controls the future: who controls the present controls the past.’ &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Orwell&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Orwell&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Orwell&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Orwell, George (2008 [1949]). &lt;em&gt;1984&lt;/em&gt;. London: Penguin. p. 37. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Orwell&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/for-they-do-not-know-what-they-are-doing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/for-they-do-not-know-what-they-are-doing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Dark Side of Germany&#39;s Economy—Aid-in-Wages</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reported &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.handelsblatt.com/politik/deutschland/zahl-der-aufstocker-steigt-hartz-iv-und-das-trotz-job/8178178.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;figures&lt;/a&gt; show that &lt;strong&gt;in Germany there are now some 1,3 million people who have to be paid allowances (‘Hartz IV’) to lift their income just a bit above the subsistence level&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This trend which started in the early 2000s with the social and economic reform program (‘Agenda 2010’) is mostly described in perspective of the (involuntary and voluntary) unemployed. It is said that a ‘social market economy’ (‘soziale Marktwirtschaft’) can only survive in the 21st century when every able-bodied is made to work even if his/her work is not productive enough to pay sufficient remuneration. If that should be the case the state is going to step in with extra payments (‘Aufstockung’) for relief. All in all it will be better for the employed, the claim goes, because lower unemployment means a better position for the individual worker to bargain for a higher wage. &lt;strong&gt;This was part and parcel of the then hyped new social democratic ideology, the ‘Third Way’&lt;/strong&gt; (in Germany the slogan was ‘Neue Mitte’) &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:BlairSchroeder&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:BlairSchroeder&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of course conservatives and liberals liked the concept and carried it on when they got elected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, it was kind of easy to enforce this policy because it did not meet criticism by strong trade unions. On the one hand working conditions (i.e. the contractual relationship between employer and employed) were already fragmented in a way that ever more working people were not associated in anymore in any form. On the other hand in nationalist-corporatist fashion the &lt;strong&gt;existing trade unions even joined forces with the government and the private business sector to keep wage increases low&lt;/strong&gt; (official speech: ‘moderate Lohnsteigerungen’, in fact it amounted to stagnation of real wages) because their’s was not progressive politics anymore but only cared about the protection of the already employed and feared competition of the growing ‘reserve army’ of unemployed or new forms of ‘precarious’ employment contracts (‘atypische Beschäftigung’).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But hardly anybody ever observes this from the angle of the employers or the national economy as a whole. In fact, &lt;strong&gt;the systematic aid-in-wages can be understood as indirect subsidies for companies&lt;/strong&gt; whose business-model is simply not working. This amounts to an &lt;strong&gt;perverted incentive structure that produces wide-spread wage depression&lt;/strong&gt;. According to statistics ca. 20% of the employed now work in the low-wage-sector (‘Niedriglohnsektor’); The former chancellor Schröder (SPD, social democrats) once &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/02/08/us-germany-jobs-idUSTRE8170P120120208&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;proudly exclaimed&lt;/a&gt; at the World Economic Forum in Davos in 2005:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We have built up one of the best low wage sectors in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ongoing Euro Crisis in part is a direct consequence of this system of this systematic distortion of the price for labor&lt;/strong&gt;. The current account surplus of Germany that climbs to ever new historic highs wouldn’t have been possible without the deep cuts in the German labor-market (‘internal depreciation’; plus the favorably monetary policy of the ECB back then to safe Germany from deflation. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Koo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Koo&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Germany became ever more dependent on this export-led growth model as the sector &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tradingeconomics.com/germany/exports-of-goods-and-services-percent-of-gdp-wb-data.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;now accounts&lt;/a&gt; for about 50% of GDP. There have been numerous attempts to push Germany to do more to start-up domestic demand. For example European Commissioner for monetary affairs Olli Rehn &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/04/10/eurozone-germany-rehn-idUSB5N0CP00D20130410&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; in April:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We recommended that Germany take steps to boost domestic demand through structural reform, which we find more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, European Commissioner for social affairs Laszlo Andor &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diagoge.com/uncategorized/angela_merkels_summer_of_discontent/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;asserted&lt;/a&gt; that Belgium and France openly complained about Germany and accused the country of ‘social dumping’. Unfortunately I’m lacking the imaginative capacity to see signs of a change of course in the light of current sentiment in Germany (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bild.de/geld/wirtschaft/export/diese-laender-lieben-made-in-germany-29277348.bild.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;pride&lt;/a&gt; about being ‘world champion’ of export, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spiegel.de/wirtschaft/soziales/regierung-verweigert-sich-dem-kampf-gegen-lohndumping-a-897551.html#ref=rss&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;unwillingness&lt;/a&gt; recognize need for an improvement of domestic demand, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/23/cyprus-crisis-germans-eurozone-failures&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;belief&lt;/a&gt; that Germany ‘is paying’ for all other countries’ ‘faults’) especially given the emotional simplifications to be heard during the upcoming election campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s even a historic precedent for all this. The infamous pseudo-humanitarian Speenhamland Act of 1795&lt;/strong&gt; prominently analysed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beacon.org/productdetails.cfm?PC=1310&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Karl Polanyi (1944): &lt;em&gt;The Great Transformation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Put simply, it was a ‘poor relief’ system irrespective of the individuals’ earnings. It’s political aim was not so much to alleviate poverty alone as to protect the traditional paternalist system on which the landed class (squirearchy) rested. The consequence (assisted by anti-trade-union law) was a depression of wages and the impoverishment of the nascent working class during the Industrial Revolution in late 18th to mid 19th century England.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact the discussion about Poor Law Reform back then was &lt;strong&gt;the starting point of the political economists’ naturalistic fantasy of self-regulating markets&lt;/strong&gt; that automatically lead (only &lt;em&gt;in the long run&lt;/em&gt; of course &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Keynes&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Keynes&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) to a balanced economy and the best possible welfare-gain for society. &lt;strong&gt;More akin to a religious belief system than sound scientific opinion it saw its revival in the 1970s as Thatcherism/Reaganism and its many metastases that we now call Neoliberalism.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The devastating economic crisis – especially in Europe – we’re now facing these days is not only a consequence of this world view turned policies but also gets prolonged by it. It seems the hegemonic way to think about resolving the crisis is depressing wages (officially: ‘internal devaluation’) and ending the role of the state as an investor of last resort (officially: ‘fiscal austerity’). Let alone the economic (in the strict sense) implications &lt;strong&gt;it is striking how unaware today’s politicians are of the devastating impact of their decisions on the social fabric that will haunt us long after the economic figures will show ‘improvement’&lt;/strong&gt;. On a rhetorical level the austerity front is crumbling but what does this mean policy-wise? For the time being everything done has been too little, too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:BlairSchroeder&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cp. &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/19990819090124/http://www.labour.org.uk/views/items/00000053.html&quot;&gt;Tony Blair and Gerhard Schröder (1999): &lt;em&gt;Europe: The Third Way/Die Neue Mitte&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:BlairSchroeder&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Koo&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cp. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/richard-koo-the-entire-crisis-in-europe-started-with-a-big-ecb-bailout-of-germany-2012-6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Joe Weisenthal: ‘Richard Koo: The Entire Crisis In Europe Started With A Big ECB Bailout Of Germany’&lt;em&gt;, Business Insider&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Koo&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Keynes&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cp. recent debate about Keynes famous phrase sparked by ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nfergus/status/330733313780224001&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;stupid and tactless remarks&lt;/a&gt;’, eg. Krugman’s take &lt;a href=&quot;http://krugman.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/05/04/keynes-keynesians-the-long-run-and-fiscal-policy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Keynes&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/the-dark-side-of-germanys-economy-aid-in-wages.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/the-dark-side-of-germanys-economy-aid-in-wages.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Euro Crisis—Schäuble&#39;s Continuous Formula</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Read this sentence from Wolfgang Schäuble:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now, the tremendous political difficulty [of the EMU] lies therein that the painful efforts that result from it are immediately noticeable, but the fruits that will result from it can only be harvested later. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Schauble&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Schauble&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now then, when did he say that? No, not when he was talking about Cyprus. No, not when the Troika was dealing with Greece. Not even while complaining about France’s, Italy’s or anyone else’s unsatisfactorily competitiveness and preaching about ‘no-pain-no-gain’-austerity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually this sentence is from 1997, months before the EMU’s third phase started. The cited paper was to put pressure on then chancellor Helmut Kohl not to go weak on his knees and get the EURO going.
I wonder when we will be able to bring the harvest in. They say there is little choice in a barrel of rotten apples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Schauble&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The original German text reads: “Die enorme politische Schwierigkeit [der EMU] besteht nun darin, daß die schmerzhaften Anstrengungen, die sich daraus ergeben, sofort spürbar sind, die Früchte aber, die sich daraus ergeben werden, erst später geerntet werden können.” &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kas.de/wf/doc/kas_27799-544-1-30.pdf&quot;&gt;Schäuble, Glos, Seiters, Lamers: “Die Europäische Währungsunion: Entscheidende Bewährungsprobe”, &lt;em&gt;UiD&lt;/em&gt; 29/1997, p. 4.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Schauble&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/schaeubles-continuous-formula.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/schaeubles-continuous-formula.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Angela Merkel&#39;s Summer of Discontent?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Political parties in Germany are getting ready for a tough campaign throughout the summer for parliamentary elections in late September. As far as the euro crisis is concerned chancellor Merkel and finance minister Schäuble are trying to delay each and every step towards a comprehensive solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is due to the fact that a substantial part of the public—especially conservatives—is buying into the narrative upheld by the government that all other countries but Germany are to blame for the crisis and that there’s no alternative to austerity. But as events over the course of a week have shown, this story more and more is turning into a political dead end and it will be quite difficult to retain it until elections have been held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, when &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324874204578438250267965718.html#&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Barroso said&lt;/a&gt; austerity “reached its limits,” Merkel and her entourage &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-23/merkel-allies-slam-barroso-comments-on-easing-euro-austerity.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;turned really grumpy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then France’s socialist party made headlines when a draft paper surfaced &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/26/france-socialist-party-german-chancellor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;which condemned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the selfish intransigence of Chancellor Merkel who thinks of nothing else but the savings of depositors in Germany, the trade balance recorded in Berlin and her electoral future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course Hollande’s government &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ft.com/intl/cms/s/0/c5a9039e-b0e1-11e2-9f24-00144feabdc0.html#axzz2RsknRq00&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;tried to ease tensions&lt;/a&gt; and rejected the harsh comments, calling them “totally counter-productive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequently EU social affairs commissioner Laszlo Andor &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spiegel.de/international/europe/eu-social-affairs-commissioner-wages-in-germany-must-increase-a-897120.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;asserted&lt;/a&gt; that “saving alone does not create growth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told the press that France and Belgium are are complaining about Germany because of an unfair competitive advantage gained by wage dumping. To counter this trend Andor called for the implementation of a minimum wage in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not even twenty four hours later, the next assault came from the new Italian prime minister Enrico Letta, who was just sworn in yesterday. Standing before parliament, he &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/financialcrisis/10026332/Italian-showdown-with-Germany-as-Enrico-Letta-rejects-death-by-austerity.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;emphatically expressed:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Italy is dying from fiscal consolidation. Growth policies cannot wait any longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He argued that the EU is facing a ‘crisis of legitimacy’ and will lose the support of the citizens if it will not turn into a ‘engine of growth’ again. Tomorrow he’ll travel to Berlin and try to convince Merkel about changing course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, that the short-lived ‘austerity consensus’ is eroding completely – in a ‘double movement’ on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diagoge.com/uncategorized/heyday-of-austerity-politics-over/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;theoretical&lt;/a&gt; and political side – we will see how that plays out with the opposition parties and the German voters in general. I hope we will not witness some kind of ‘Burgfrieden’.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/angela_merkels_summer_of_discontent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/angela_merkels_summer_of_discontent.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Brendan Simms: German Strength and the Euro Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a short interview with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.polis.cam.ac.uk/contacts/staff/simms-brendan.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Brendan Simms&lt;/a&gt;, a professor of history of international relations. He talks to an editor of the &lt;em&gt;Economist&lt;/em&gt; about the past and present strength of Germany within Europe and its implications in the context of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diagoge.com/tag/eurocrisis/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;euro crisis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He explains that the appeal that Germany should “lead” doesn’t mean it should “pay more”—as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-21974496&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;public opinion&lt;/a&gt; often holds. It simply means that it’s up to Germany to invest its political capital into a reform of the EU respectively the euro zone and press for deeper integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand he believes that besides other issues the recent—hardly promising—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/22/uk-military-eu-german-minister&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;attempts&lt;/a&gt; to tie Britain more closely to the EU Germany is jeopardizing its scope in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s good to hear sane voices out there still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object id=&quot;flashObj&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; codebase=&quot;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=9,0,47,0&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;bgcolor&quot; value=&quot;#FFFFF8&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;flashVars&quot; value=&quot;videoId=2321698474001&amp;amp;linkBaseURL=http%3A%2F%2Fecon.st%2F16lgXZy&amp;amp;playerID=1425961410001&amp;amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAABDH-R__E~,dB4S9tmhdOo20g03jDsDgNBGDcclfHEU&amp;amp;domain=embed&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;swLiveConnect&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;autoStart&quot; value=&quot;false&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowScriptAccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFF8&quot; flashvars=&quot;videoId=2321698474001&amp;amp;linkBaseURL=http%3A%2F%2Fecon.st%2F16lgXZy&amp;amp;playerID=1425961410001&amp;amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAABDH-R__E~,dB4S9tmhdOo20g03jDsDgNBGDcclfHEU&amp;amp;domain=embed&amp;amp;dynamicStreaming=false&quot; base=&quot;http://admin.brightcove.com&quot; name=&quot;flashObj&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; seamlesstabbing=&quot;false&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; swliveconnect=&quot;true&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; pluginspage=&quot;http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/brendan-simms-german-strength-and-the-euro-crisis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/brendan-simms-german-strength-and-the-euro-crisis.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Varieties of Capitalism and the Euro Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s an interesting recording of a public lecture at LSE by Peter Hall about the euro crisis from the perspective of the varieties-of-capitalism approach in political science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, this approach states that in order to fully understand the functioning of a capitalist economy one has to look beyond the mere theory of market liberalism. The economy is not all about abstract technicalities of equilibria of supply and demand mediated by the price mechanism in free markets. Rather &lt;strong&gt;the whole institutional configuration, rooted in far-reaching historical developments, of any given society has to be part of the analysis&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Hall identifies different types of economies within the European Monetary Union (EMU) which pursue different kinds of midterm growth strategies. The ‘northern’ types, exemplified by Germany, follow an &lt;strong&gt;export led strategy&lt;/strong&gt; while the ‘southern’ types, exemplified by Spain, follow a (domestic) &lt;strong&gt;demand led strategy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That it will be quite problematic to put those distinct economies under the umbrella of a single currency, because now they lack the former balancing mechanism of (national) currency appreciation/depreciation, is evident today in the midst of the euro crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the interesting question Hall asks is, why at all was the EMU created and why was it created in it’s particular form? The &lt;strong&gt;main interest of the states that established the EMU in the 1990s, Hall argues, was to escape the torturous process of coordinating the monetary mechanism&lt;/strong&gt; that was in place at the time. Secondly, he thinks that it was not seen important for the design of the EMU to have some sort of coordinated midterm fiscal policy because the &lt;strong&gt;prevailing economic doctrine was dominated by rational expectations theory&lt;/strong&gt;, which holds fiscal policy to only have negative effects anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the survival of the EMU will depend on the possibility to reach an agreement for the establishment of an &lt;strong&gt;institutional framework that could guarantee the coordination of such a midterm fiscal policy&lt;/strong&gt; to bring about a certain economic balance again. However, Hall sees a bumpy road ahead, because &lt;strong&gt;there is no common diagnosis about what are the root causes of the euro crisis&lt;/strong&gt;. Thus the prescription for a cure is different too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fear the German ‘doctor’ went on vacation (ie. election campaign trail) and will return not until September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KYWrHiFCA8k&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/varieties-of-capitaslism-and-the-euro-crisis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mo-tom.github.io//thoughts/varieties-of-capitaslism-and-the-euro-crisis.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
